Cameron Smith

csmith158@butlercc.edu | 316-746-4961

Biography

Hi! I'm a junior front-end web developer who's been self-learning ever since I was ten years old. I'm graduating in May 2018, I've played with a lot of technologies, such as **HTML**, **CSS**, **JavaScript**, **jQuery**, **and Bootstrap** for websites. I've started a website hosting and website development company in 2009 that helped local businesses establish a web presence by creating, hosting, and maintaining their company website and email server. I'm a Microsoft **MTA 98-361** certified "*Software Developer*" in the **C#** language. I've made 2D & 3D games in **C++**, **SDL**, **C#**, **XNA**, and with commercial engines such as **Unity3D** and **Unreal Engine**.

Education

DEVRY UNIVERSITY (2010-2011)

- · Major: Game & Simulation Programming
- · Awarded Dean's Honor List

BUTLER COMMUNITY COLLEGE (2017-CURRENT)

- · Major: Software Development
- · Graduating May 2018.
- · Currently maintaining a 3.89 GPA.
- · Awarded Dean's Honor List.

Technology Summary

LANGUAGES

- · Web: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP
- · Software: C#, C++, C, Java, Python

FRAMEWORKS/LIBRARIES

- · Web: Bootstrap, jQuery
- · Software: XNA, SDL, SFML

MISCELLANEOUS

- · Operating Systems: Windows, Mac, Linux
- · Version control: Git, GitHub, SVN

Experience

BOASTHOSTING, LLC (2009-2010)

Founder

- · Provided website hosting services to individuals and local businesses.
- · Developed websites for production use in HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap using jQuery.
- · Maintained customer websites (bug fixes, small feature requests, assist with 3rd party plugins).

· Provided integration services with customer's existing website into WHMCS.

XENON SERVERS (2009-2015)

General Manager

- · Started as a tier 1 technical support agent.
- · Aided with installation, customization, hardening, and integration of vBulletin.
- · Aided with integration of production website into WHMCS.
- · Made small maintenance changes to production website, used in-house build tools to deploy.
- · Wrote documentation for internal tools and public knowledgebase articles for end-users.

Links

- · Portfolio: http://czsmith.me/
- · GitHub: https://github.com/cameronzsmith/
- · LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/csmith158/
- ArtStation: https://www.artstation.com/czsmith7